<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Scrolling Text</string>
    <string name="romantic_poem">Romantic Poem</string>
    <string name="textview">
        <b>5 Great Romantic Poems</b>\n
        <i>By Yuvraj pareek Updated April 27, 2021</i>\n\n\n
Great romantic poems can come from any age, but they all share a commonality of resonating with today readers. There a large range of love poems from the most desperate to the humblest prose. Here are five great romantic poems to inspire your heart.\n\n\n


1). <b>Romantic Poem About Humble Love </b>\n\n
Walt Whitman poem, "A Glimpse," is one of the great romantic poems about humble love. Rather than an over-the-top, embellished poem, this one is about the simple feeling of love shared between two lovers in a busy bar\n. At the end, he wrote, "There we two, content, happy in being together, / speaking little, perhaps not a word."\n\n\n

2). <b>Timeless and Romantic Poem </b>\n\n
Elizabeth Barrett wrote the poem, "How Do I Love Thee" sometime between 1806 and 1861. While it has been a long time since the poem was written, it still resonates with modern readers in deep and meaningful ways\n. The beginning lines are probably one of the most striking as it starts, "How do I love thee? Let me count the ways." From there, she goes on to describe all the ways in which she loves her lover.\n\n\n



3). <b>Contemporary Romantic Poem </b>\n\n
"When a Woman Loves a Man" by David Lehman is a superb example of a romantic contemporary poem. He lists all of the scenarios based on when a man or woman love one another and describes both the good and bad aspects in a relationship\n. He talks about breakups and make ups but, at the end, resolves the poem with a powerful six lines where he describes the beauty of the nature that surrounds him in awe as "he watches her sleep, thinking: / as midnight to the moon is sleep to the beloved."\n\n\n



4). <b>Romantic Poem Dedicated to Marriage </b>\n\n
"To My Dear and Loving Husband" by Anne Bradstreet is a terrific example of a poem written about marriage. There plenty of poetry about the moment of falling in love or the feelings of infatuation, but the love that conquers all is a different kind. In the poem, the poet describes how she loves her husband, noting that "Thy love is such I can no way repay, / The heavens reward thee manifold I pray."\n\n\n


5). <b>Romantic Verse From the Bible </b>\n\n
1 Corinthians 13:4-8 has become one of the most well-known verses in the Bible when it comes to the subject of love\n. It can apply to many different types of relationships, including romantic ones. It reminds everyone the pure nature of love and starts off with the unforgettable line, "Love is patient, love is kind."\n\n\n





    </string>

</resources>